ONYEBUEKE IFEANYI SAMUEL

https://www.linkedin.com/in/onyebueke-ifeanyi-1b52411b4/

onyebuekes93@gmail.com www.github.com/Samuel202093 https://samuel-onyebueke.netlify.app

EXPERIENCE

RioTech — Full Stack Developer

February 2023 - April 2024

I collaborated with designers to translate design mockups into functional web applications, ensuring seamless integration between front-end and back-end components. Monitored application performance and addressed any bugs or errors that arose.

Loc Tech I.T Institute, Port-Harcourt — *Web development Bootcamp*

April 2021 - December 2022

I participated in an intensive coding bootcamp, honing my programming skills and collaborating with other students to develop innovative projects.

EDUCATION

Federal Polytechnic Oko, Anambra — HND

November 2016 - November 2018

Computer Engineering

Federal Polytechnic Oko, Anambra — ND

October 2013 - August 2015

Computer Engineering

Immanuel Comprehensive High School, Port-Harcourt —

WAEC

September 2005 - August 2011

WAEC

PROJECTS

JobHunt Web Application

ABOUT

Gender: Male

Language: English

PROFILE

Analytical-minded and creative team player with a strong background in Computer Engineering who is keen in applying academic foundation and technical experience. Accustomed to providing integral technical support. Experience in Microsoft Word, Website Design and Development and also have the ability to function independently and in fast-paced team environments.

SKILLS

Proficient in Html5, Css, Tailwind Css, Javascript, ReactJs, Redux, Bootstrap, Typescript, NodeJs, Expressjs, Php, Laravel, Graphql, MongoDb, MySql, Postgresql and DevOps in View, computer literacy, efficient time management, excellent communication, adept to new technologies, team-player, excellent

Github link:

https://github.com/Samuel202093/jobsite laravel project

Technologies: Html5, Css, Javascript, Php, Laravel, Mysql.

E-commerce Web Application

Link: https://hi-gadget.netlifv.app/

Github link:

https://github.com/Samuel202093/e-commerce-frontend, https://github.com/Samuel202093/e-commerce-server-side

Technologies: Html5, Css, Javascript, ReactJs, Redux, react-router-dom, react-icons, ChartJs, NodeJs, Express, JWT, Nodemailer, MongoDb, stripe.

Description: I developed the frontend of the application using html5, css, javascript, reactjs, chartjs, redux, react-router-dom. The react-router-dom was used to handle routing in the application, redux which is an external state management library was used to manage states within the application and chartjs were used for data visualization by admin.

Furthermore, I built the backend of the application using Nodejs, Express, JWT, Nodemailer, Stripe, MongoDb, Stripe. I built a CRUD Restful Api for admin using express, JWT was used for user authentication, Nodemailer was used for email verification, Stripe was my payment gateway and Mongodb was used as my database to save users and products data.

Data Entry Application(Backend)

Github link: https://github.com/Samuel202093/exam server

Technologies: NodeJs, Express, JWT, Postgresql, Cloudinary, Knex.

Description: I built the application using the aforementioned technologies. In the application certain tasks can only be carried out by the admin in which this was achieved by authentication and authorization using JWT. I handled file uploads using cloudinary to optimize the server and also I integrated knex which is an sql query-builder with postgresql to save data to the database.

Admin Dashboard

Link: https://typescriptadmindashboard.netlify.app/

Github link:

https://github.com/Samuel202093/Typescript_Admin_Dashboard

Technologies: Html5, TailwindCss, Javascript, ReactJs, Typescript, UseContext, react-router-dom, Zod, react-icons.

Description: I built the application using reactjs and typescript. TailwindCss was used for styling of the application, react-router-dom was used for routing, react-icons for integrating icons and useContext was used for handling state and Zod for form handling.

problem-solving, creative ability and logical approach to work.

CERTIFICATIONS

English_for_IT 1 & 2 by Cisco.

Career Essentials in Software Development by Linkedin and Microsoft.

Career Essentials in System
Administration by Linkedin and
Microsoft.

Career Essentials in Generative AI by Linkedin and Microsoft.

REFEREES

Mr. Igbe Cletus

Software Engineer C.E.O Netcle Technologies Tel: 07060722008

Mr. Duff Ini. D. Caleb

Software Instructor Rivers I.C.T Center(Techcreek) **Tel:** 08068800748